A few days ago, we uploaded a video on the
difference between critical illness insurance
and health insurance plans. You saw
that both are different plans.
Critical illnesses are covered in your health insurance,
but for maximum benefits, it is
necessary to take a critical illness insurance plan. So today we have brought for you the
top five critical illness insurance
plans for 2024. We did research and
saw which plans are available
in the market and have brought the top five of them
for you. So, I would like to tell you that you
must do your due diligence here
before entering into any insurance policy. We are
sharing this information with you on the basis of our research, but
please do your due diligence when ever you are
buying your insurance policy. Let's move on to the
video and talk about the top five
critical illness insurance plans for
2024. We will compare ISC Lombard
CritiShield Plan, Bajaj Alliance
CritiCare Plan, Niva Bupa CritiCare, Aditya
Birla Active Secure.  Critical Illness
ADFC ERGO Critical Illness Plan
Platinum Before starting the video I would
like to introduce myself
for those who are new my name is Gurleen
Kau Takku I am a Certified Financial
Planner I have been associated with the insurance industry for the last 18 years
and every week I
bring videos for you so that
your personal financial life can become easy and
happy because the tagline of our company is
also creating a wealth of
happiness let's move towards the video
a quick reminder before that if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel do it so that
you get the right information at the
right time so first we will talk about the
ICR of all these insurance companies their
claim ratio and then we will talk
about the other benefits so their claim
ratio is III Lombard's 77.333100
Bupa's is 54.0 Aditya Birla's is 64.6 and
hdfcergo.com
has 15 illnesses covered means if those listed  If
some of the illnesses are diagnosed for the
first time, then the lump sum
payout will be given, whichever time shot you choose.
Every company has listed illnesses, like
we talked about 92, 64, 20, 43 and 15. So,
we will share with you the list of illnesses in those illnesses. If
any of those illnesses is diagnosed, then
you get the claim. That list is in
front of you, you can refer to it. For example, the
list of ICSE Lombard Critical Care Scheme has a
list of 92 illnesses. There
are five buckets here, the first bucket is called
cancer and blood, the second is heart and blood, the
third is major organs, the fourth is nervous
system and the fifth is other illnesses. So, if
anything happens in these five buckets, then the lump sum
payout will be given equal to the time shot
that you choose. Similarly, in Bajaj ANS Critical Care
Plan, you have five sections, so the five
sections are cancer care, cardiovascular.  Kidney
Care, Neuro Care,
Transplants and Sensory Organ Care, if
any of these is diagnosed then a
lump sum payout will be made equal to your sum
short. Similarly, Niva Booba Critical Care
Plan has this list of 20 illnesses which
is on your screen. In Aditya Birla,
as I told you, there are three plans,
Plan One which covers 20 illnesses,
Plan Two which covers 50 illnesses
and Plan Three covers 64 illnesses.
In ADAC Ergo Critical Illness Plan, these are the 15
illnesses which are on your list and these are
covered for you. If these are diagnosed then a lump
sum payout will be made. If you have opted
for this policy, then
like in ISI Lombard, there is a concept of major illness and minor illness, the
major illness will be diagnosed and that is
listed for you, which are the major
illnesses, major illness. If
any major illness is diagnosed from each bucket, then there will be
100% sum short payout.  If a minor
illness is diagnosed, then 50% sum short
payout will be made. Its detailed video of
ICCI Lombard Critical Shield Plan is also on our channel,
you can refer that too
if you want to buy this plan.
Jazz Lens Critical Care Plan has
category A and category B. If
any illness occurs from category A, then it will be
given at 25%. If it is from category B,
then 100% will be paid. There are
two options in Niva Bupa Critical Plan. Option one
is lump sum payout which is 100% of sum shield, which
means whatever sum you have taken, for example,
50 lakhs, if any of those 20 illnesses is
diagnosed, then 50 lakhs will be paid out.
You will be given sum short at 10%
every year for 5 years. So basically,
payout is happening at 150%. Currently, 100% is being given to
you at 50%, divided in 5 years.  If you are giving it by doing this then if
you choose that option then the
premium will be charged accordingly so the
premium of both the options is different
in Aditya Birla the simple concept is whichever plan
you have taken whether plan one or two
or three is according to your number of
illnesses in ADFC Go there are 15 illnesses that are
yours if any is diagnosed then sum
payout will be made equal to the sum sum
that you have chosen so let's talk a little about the
eligibility criteria now let's talk about the
minimum and maximum sum sum
in ISI Lombard Criti Shield Plan the minimum sum sum is 5 lakh and maximum is
40 lakh in Bajaj Ans Criti Shield Plan the
minimum sum sum is 1 lakh and maximum is 50
lakh in ISI Lombard Criti Shield Plan the
minimum sum sum is 5 lakh and maximum
is 40 lakh so let's assume if you
choose 40 lakh then you will get 40 lakh for each bucket
i.e. 40 lakh  Your bucket one, bucket two, bucket
three, bucket four, bucket five, which are listed
buckets, will get Rs. 40 lakh each, so
if you talk about the cover in one way, it
is an insurance of Rs. 2 crore, it is an insurance of Rs. 2 crore
because there are 40 * 5 different buckets, so
if any illness is diagnosed in whichever bucket,
that bucket will be given and you
can continue the rest of the buckets as long as you want by paying the
premium,
Bajaj Ans Criti Sheel Plan has an option from Rs. 1 lakh to Rs.
50 lakh and if you have chosen
more than one section, then
your maximum sum assured can be only Rs. 2 crore, so
as I told you, the
sum assured of different sections is different, now here
also suppose if you choose five sections, then the
maximum sum assured can be only Rs. 2 crore, it will
not be more than Rs. 2 crore, so
hence you will not be able to choose five sections, you will be
able to choose only four, if you want to take Rs. 50 lakh
for each section, or you  You
can define that I want 20 lakhs from this section,
30 lakhs from this section and so on. The maximum sum assured
of all the sections combined will not exceed 2 crores.
In Bajaj Alliance policy, there is an option of Rs
3 lakh to Rs 2 crore in Niva Bupa Critical Care Plan.
You can choose the
sum assured you want. In Aditya Birla, there is an
option of Rs 1 lakh to Rs 1 crore. In
HDFC, there is an option of up to Rs 50 lakhs. You can choose according to
your needs. Now we will talk about the
minimum entry age. The minimum entry age
in III Lombard is 3 months. The maximum
entry age is 65 years. You
can enter this policy from 3 months to 65 years. In
Bajaj Alliance, you can enter this policy from 3 months to 65 years. The
dependent age is 30 years. In Niva Bupa, the
minimum entry age is 18 years. The maximum is
65 years in Plan One in Aditya Birla.  The
minimum entry age in Plan 2 is five
years and the minimum entry age in Plan 3
is 18 years because it
covers the maximum number of illnesses, so they are not offering it to children but only to adults
and the maximum
entry age is 65 years for both the plans. The
minimum
entry age in ADAC is five years and the maximum entry age is
65 years. All five policies have
lifelong renewability, which means if you
buy the policy today, you can continue it for life
till the time you are paying the
premium. But as I told you, if a
critical illness is diagnosed, then
usually that policy gets discontinued and you
cannot renew it further if even one
critical illness is diagnosed. But this is
not the case with ICICI Lombard Crit Shield.
If one bucket is used up,
you can continue the other bucket as long as you
want. Now let's talk about the
additional benefits in ICICI Lombard Crit
Shield.  There are some additional benefits which is
called personal accidental benefit,
you can choose that by paying additional
premium, in that your accidental death
PPD which is permanent total disability
and permanent partial disability PPD
is also covered, cancer restore cover
is also optional, you can choose that over and
now your buckets, which are five buckets, there is
also cancer restore cover above that, now let's talk about the
additional benefits
in your Bajaj ANS, so these additional benefits are
part of the policy, that is, there is cancer
reconstructive surgery in it, 10 per cent off sum
maximum 2 lakh, if you are diagnosed with cancer, then
separately for cancer reconstructive surgery you will get up to ₹2000000
whichever is lower, cardiac nursing is also there,
if the claim is paid, in section B there were two
sections, section A and section B,
in section B, if the claim is paid for cardiovascular surgery, then
5 per cent off sum shot is given  The
maximum claim amount will be Rs 50,000 for dialysis care.
If the claim amount is for kidney care in section B,
then Rs 10 per sum assured or
maximum Rs 1 lakh for physiotherapy care. If the
claim amount is for neuro care in section B, then Rs 5 per sum
assured or maximum Rs
50,000 for sensory care.
If you use transplant or sensory neuro
care in section B, then Rs 5 per sum assured or
maximum Rs 5,000,000 will be given to you. So, there is
no additional benefit in Niva PAP
which is separate. You will only be given a lump sum payout.
And as I told you, there is an
option to choose option one and option two, in
which you are given 100% lump sum or
100% and Rs 10 per every year for 5 years,
then Rs 150 payout is given as per the premium decided.
So, there is no
additional benefit in Aditya Billa Active Secure Illness also.
Same  Goes for ADAC ERGO
Critical Illness Plan. So now we will talk about
in which format you can take this policy.
For example, ICSA Lombard, you
can take individual and multi-individual policy.
Family floater policy is not available.
Bajaj Alliance's policy is available at individual level.
Niva Bpa and both family floater and
individual options are available. You
can choose.
Individual and multi-individual is
available in Aditya Birla and
individual and multi-individual
is also available in ADAC Ergo. Now let's talk about waiting periods. There is a
waiting period which is called
initial waiting period. It means that
your claim will not be settled during that time. If any claim
comes, then the initial waiting period in ICSA Lombard Critical Shield is
90 days.
In Aditya Birla plan, the initial waiting
period is 180 days. In Niva Bpa, the
initial waiting period in Aditya Birla is 90 days.  The
initial waiting period in is 90 days
and HDFC Ergo also has an initial waiting
period. The survival period is 90 days. The
survival period is that
after the critical illness is diagnosed, you have to
survive for a minimum number of days due to
which you get the claim.
Only after that you get the claim. There is
no survival period mentioned in the ICAC Lombard plan. If there is a
diagnosis, the claim will be paid. There is
no need to fulfill the survival period. In the Bajaj Alliance Critical Plan,
you have a survival period of seven days and 15 days. It
is necessary to fulfill them for different conditions, only then the claim will be paid.
Rewa Bupa has a survival period of 30 days.
Aditya Birla has a
survival period of 15 days. In ADFC Ergo, you
can choose the survival period, 15 days
or 30 days. You can give this choice while buying the policy.
All our policies
are available for one year, two years and three years.
Except ADFC ERGO, ADFC ERGO is
available for one year and two years only.
Here, when you go to buy a critical illness insurance
policy, there are some eligibility criteria for that too.
You are given a policy according to your income. So,
if you are earning, then in case of earning,
you get a sum assured up to 12 times your gross income.
Suppose your
income is Rs 10 lakh, then you can take an insurance policy and get cover up to Rs 1 crore 20 lakh. If there is a
non-earning spouse, then 50%
of the proposal sum assured, which is the sum assured of the husband
or the sum assured of the wife, will be
given to the spouse, which has been proposed to the proposer,
or Rs lakh, whichever is
lower. So, these are some common conditions that
apply. In all the policies,
in case of children, % of the proposal sum assured is given
or maximum  ₹ lakh which ever is
lower. There are some things which are excluded
from the critical illnesses which are common,
rest you can check policy to policy.
What are some common illnesses? First is
if any critical illness occurs due to sexually transmitted disease, then it will not be given.
This is a non-disclosed disease. You
took the policy and did not disclose that
problem that you already had that pre-
existing condition and later the same gets
converted into a critical illness. At the
time of critical illness claim, if the
company comes to know that there was some non-
disclosure, then the claim will not be given.
If you abuse alcohol or drugs, then
also the claim will not be given, that is,
any self-inflicted disease.
Suppose someone's liver gets damaged due to excessive alcohol
and some chronic condition or
critical condition occurs, then the claim will not be given
due to excessive alcohol.
If any problem arises due to excessive smoking, then the claim will not be given.  Due to this, there is a
problem in the lungs, you have lung cancer,
I am giving you an example, then the claim will
not be paid because it is self-
inflicted, you knew that this is wrong
thing, still you were doing it, then the claim will not be paid,
if the conjunctivitis was a birth defect and while undergoing
treatment for it, you develop a critical
illness, then also it will not be paid, conjunctivitis is a
defect by birth, and
if any critical illness occurs due to war or natural calamity, then also the
claim will
not be paid, these are some common exclusions,
a specific list of exclusions, you
can refer to the policy you want to buy,
anyway you will do due diligence,
before buying the policy, look carefully and
buy the policy properly, and critical illness
is also important because critical illness
is also called living death because the
survival rate of critical illness has
increased so much, earlier it used to happen that
death occurred due to critical illness,
but what is the situation now  Because the survival rate is
high, the treatment is high for everything,
so living death is also said that because of that
your expenses increase,
earning capacity reduces, so
if you get a lump sum benefit, that will be
helpful. Now in the last, I am sharing the premium with you,
you can refer to all the plans and check
which plan suits you as per the
list of critical illnesses. I hope
you will find this video useful to buy your
critical illness health insurance policy.
Please again I am requesting giving a
disclaimer, please do your due diligence
before buying the policy. This is not a
product recommendation. This is just giving information about
different products. You should
buy the policy only after doing your due diligence and looking at the details and do
not buy the policy without any disclosure. And before leaving,
a quick reminder, if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do so, so that you get
the right information at
the right time. See you next time.  Till then
stay safe take care with new topic in video bye bye